now global insurance funds have
identified kenya as a gateway to the
african insurance industry and what they
say is due to a positive trend in
insurance consumption a favorable
business climate and advanced
technological infrastructure in the
country national treasury principal
secretary dr julius moyes said that
kenya possesses a number of qualities
that make it a natural hub for
businesses that operate in africa
supported by growing middle class and
high value goods and services
[Music]
underwriters are optimistic saying they
see demand for insurance growing as the
population doubles with a large appetite
for innovative insurance products they
add it is an opportunity for them to
deepen the insurance understanding of
the sector
what we're finding as we look at the
various markets in africa including
kenya is that with increasing prosperity
with economic growth but the demand for
insurance is only getting higher and
higher the government says it is
creating a conducive environment by
developing a robust economic framework
as a gateway for institutions to set
base in kenya we are going to have to
demonstrate
how kenya is going to gain from creating
this new environment
we are going to show
how kenya will benefit from offering the
incentives that they're going to offer
through the nifc there is now a new
operating framework
which we have developed
that provides a gateway for institutions
like prudential to establish and grow
their business in the country this is
designed to offer an efficient and
predictable operating environment
which is progressive
uh with economic incentives our regional
team which now being here in nairobi
rather than in london will of course be
much much much closer to our customers
and will be able to provide stronger and
better support
to our businesses and to all of our
people throughout africa
speaking during the launch of prudential
plc's africa office national treasury
principal secretary dr julius moyer
urged global firms to also take
advantage of a diverse partnership
offering through green financing to
safeguard against climate change as a
unique challenge in the region it
requires coordinated partnerships to
mobilize
sustainable finance both from the public
and the private sectors
in order to meet the huge financing and
financial challenges that arise
prudential plc becomes the first
institution to be admitted to the
nairobi international financial center
the global underwriter hopes to make
inroads in the african insurance market
from its nairobi base